<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Val Knight&#39;s Text Dumping Ground</title>
    <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Val Knight&#39;s Text Dumping Ground</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Content licensed under NPLv2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:05:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.valknight.xyz/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming the Cookstar</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2021-01/becoming-the-cookstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2021-01/becoming-the-cookstar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;subtitle class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;How A Bad Video Game got me into speedrunning&lt;/subtitle&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-sucked-in&#34;&gt;Getting sucked in&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I got into a certain Hot New Trend in speedrunning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cooking Mama: Cookstar (for Nintendo Switch)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who hasn&amp;rsquo;t kept up, Cookstar is the Cooking Mama game so bad it got pulled from sale and the license holder - Office Create - talked about legal action against the developer. It&amp;rsquo;s wild and while I won&amp;rsquo;t be recapping &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, I recommend you go take a skim of the Wikipedia page if you&amp;rsquo;re curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honest is something I aspire to be, so, full transparency - I&amp;rsquo;m not being creative here. The amazing Laura Kate Dale (@LauraKBuzz on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LaurakBuzz&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Twitch, YouTube, Patreon, etc) posted the following, on January 7th&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Surprise daytime stream.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to try and perform a world record speedrun live on stream.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let&amp;#39;s become the world&amp;#39;s fastest Cooking Mama: Cookstar (All Vegetatian Recipies - Any %) player.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sure, I&amp;#39;ll be the only time listed, still counts.&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Ze3GjKifhm&#34;&gt;https://t.co/Ze3GjKifhm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/9eWAH7OQUb&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9eWAH7OQUb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Laura Kate Dale (@LaurakBuzz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LaurakBuzz/status/1347134615690088448?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On first glance, I saw this, thought &amp;ldquo;haha, that&amp;rsquo;s funny, all the best&amp;rdquo; and tuned in for a little bit before having to close my browser to go to a meeting. When I returned post meeting, and Laura (still on the same run) mentioned that she would love for someone to challenge her time, I took it upon to challenge her, live, on Twitch, to a new time. Is this what ten months of pandemic brain does to a woman? Sure. But, my streams are usually about four hours long, and, if I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a time at least I could say I came second and it would be a funny addition to a Twitter bio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I signed up to SpeedRun.com, ordered a Chef hat, and posted the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;HELLO.&lt;br&gt;TOMORROW.&lt;br&gt;7PM.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I will attempt to take &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LaurakBuzz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@LaurakBuzz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Cooking Mama Cookstar All Vegetarian Recipes 3:54:56 on Twitch&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a chef outfit (if it arrives on time)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(I&amp;#39;ll most probably fail but it&amp;#39;s gonna be pretty funny regardless!)&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/zuEOFeW767&#34;&gt;https://t.co/zuEOFeW767&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_VKni?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@_VKni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Val the Anime Rival Cookstar (@VallerieKnight) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/VallerieKnight/status/1347619079843143684?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;challenging-what-i-thought-speedruns-were&#34;&gt;Challenging what I thought speedruns were&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading into this I thought speedruns were things people who &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; loved a game did, and required great skill - the kind of persom who runs the same level of the same game for years, to get tenths upon tenths of a second of improvement. This kind of thing, to be frank, scared me a little - making my speedrun.com account felt like the equivalent of diving head first into a boulder trained in mixed martial arts. I saw dozens upon dozens of people on the Cooking Mama 2 leaderboard, all of whom were competing to be at the very top, with times in the couple of minutes or less on the (admittedly, very entertaining to watch) &amp;ldquo;Burn A Pie%&amp;rdquo; category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of &amp;ldquo;enjoying the game as something else&amp;rdquo; hit like a brick during the first run I did - it was something which was a whole lot of fun which I did not expect to have with such an awful game. From joking about the carrots just being stretched diamonds, to the wonderful art someone in my chat produced (which I am so gracious for - a link to the tweet with the art + their Twitter should be linked below, check them out!), it was strangely one of the best times I had playing games in such a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/VallerieKnight?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@VallerieKnight&lt;/a&gt; Congrats on your Cooking Mama world record time! It was a fun being there with ya! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/S0Qn2GVdMO&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/S0Qn2GVdMO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Miss Genki Art (commissions open) (@MissGenkiArt) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MissGenkiArt/status/1348041614493552640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-competition&#34;&gt;The Competition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this, I kinda was a little worried by competing - I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to upset anyone by taking their times, and I certaintly didn&amp;rsquo;t want to step on anyone&amp;rsquo;s toes by being the Weirdo who @s you on Twitter implying &amp;ldquo;Haha I&amp;rsquo;m better than you at video games 😆🤭&amp;rdquo; when in fact I just wanted to see if I could get a good time as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that has stuck out is how far this worry has been from what actually happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone in the handful of people competing have always seemed to be welcoming of new times. Receiving the news that Laura &lt;em&gt;somehow&lt;/em&gt; got a sub 13 on 5 recipes was amazing - even though I got beaten, it meant we knew for sure that we could go further, and continue to get the most out of this pretty bad video game. The joke about me being Laura&amp;rsquo;s anime rival is entertaining to me, a little out of being confused as to how I got here, but also amazement into how far this healthy back and forth has gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The welcoming of new times set by others is something I at least love, as they give me motivation to load the game one more time, listen to that obnoxious music, and see if I can one up Laura or Dan and get back to the #1 spot. Even those playing other Cooking Mama games (like the mods of the leaderboards) have been incredibly lovely and welcoming - something that&amp;rsquo;s a stark contrast to many other competitive scenes I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to stumble into in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect was how good it was not only to compete in times, but compete in knowledge - finding out the new skips and sharing them feels equally as good (to me) as getting a new time, and I&amp;rsquo;m just as proud of my discoveries. Figuring out the differences between &lt;code&gt;v1.0&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;v1.0.2&lt;/code&gt; of the game &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have felt horrible as it led to my times getting de-listed, but I was welcoming my times getting delisted with open arms as something &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; helped research went into that decision!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speedrunning Cookstar has been so much fun. Even if my times right now aren&amp;rsquo;t looking like the best, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to go get them down (at some point). That might just be the fact I enjoy repetitive actions, but I also do enjoy the healthy sense of discovery from this. Beyond that, creating a (however small) bit of joy and entertainment for people has been so fun - talking back and forth with chat, defending my controversial opinions about Mario 3D World being more enjoyable than Mario Galaxy (a hill I will die on) or even just providing the antagonist character for whenever the anime adaptation is picked up by Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if right now, I&amp;rsquo;m going off and playing actually &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; games, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad, for a few hours, I could truly call myself the Cookstar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning the following people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LauraKBuzz&#34;&gt;Laura Kate Dale&lt;/a&gt; for kickstarting the popularity of veggie any% 50 recipe category, and for being such a wonderful competitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Super_NinDando&#34;&gt;Super_NinDando&lt;/a&gt; for wandering in as the third amazing competitor, and developing procon slicing strats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My good friend 
&lt;a href=&#34;javascript:void(0);&#34; onclick=&#34;alert(&#39;He doesn\&#39;t use Twitter or other public social media, sorry!&#39;)&#34;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;  who is partially the reason I bought this awful garbage game in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Switch homebrew scene for developing the tools I used to remove updates from the game and do research - shoutouts to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Atmosphere-NX/Atmosphere&#34;&gt;Atmosphere&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/XorTroll/Goldleaf&#34;&gt;Goldleaf&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CTCaer/hekate&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CTCaer/hekate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone who I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned who has been following along, whether on twitter or in my Twitch chat for being good company during these four hour streams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Wanted to Do Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/i-wanted-to-do-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 15:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/i-wanted-to-do-photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been having thoughts for a while about how the compsci community has a really nasty feeling towards the arts. For example, the amount of jokes about arts degrees landing you a job in a coffee shop and that compsci is the One Good Field is frustrating to no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;14-year-old-vallerie&#34;&gt;14 Year Old Vallerie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go back, to 14-year-old Vallerie. I just got my first proper camera and fell in love with it. The photos were kinda bad, even for a 14-year-old, but even then, it was such a freeing thing, especially as I&amp;rsquo;ve never been big into painting or drawing. Going into college, I so badly wanted to do Photography. So badly. But, because I did well in Maths and Physics, I felt the pressure on me to do STEM things instead. Every time I heard of friends talking about their photography projects they were doing in class, I felt my soul get absolutely crushed, as, that was something I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bad-approach-to-teaching&#34;&gt;Bad Approach to Teaching&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kinda seeped into changing my feelings about the narrative of &amp;ldquo;We should teach kids to code!&amp;rdquo; that&amp;rsquo;s been pushed by the government here in the UK for about the past 10 years, while cutting school budgets (with the arts always being the first to feel this tightening of budgets).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.valknight.xyz/images/personal/i-wanted-to-do-photography/guardian.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Screenshot of a guardian article titled &amp;#34;Coding at school: a new parent&amp;#39;s guide to England&amp;#39;s computing curriculum&amp;#34;&#34;   /&gt;
    
      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;right&#34; &gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/sep/04/coding-school-computing-children-programming&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/sep/04/coding-school-computing-children-programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re always told that kids need to learn to program because it helps with &amp;ldquo;problem-solving&amp;rdquo; and that we &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nEeD mOrE grADuATes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Personally, I think this is horrific. We should teach things because knowledge is valuable, not because big companies want new fresh code machines to sit at a desk and write another frontend for a database all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-to-do&#34;&gt;What to do&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, given the state of UK politics (very not good), I doubt this will change soon. As such, us compsci folks need to do more to promote cool projects that support the arts. One thing I adore is the project &lt;a href=&#34;https://processing.org&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt; which aims to promote &amp;ldquo;software literacy within the visual arts and visual literacy within technology&amp;rdquo;. This leads me into killing the awful stigma we have towards the arts, and specifically, those pursuing the arts at academic institutions like universities. (People who do/have done creative things as your degree or as your job, you&amp;rsquo;re HELLA COOL and I love all of you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping this up, this is a very long and disjointed way to write if you are in the same position of 14-year old Vallerie, and have a skill you so desperately want to pursue, do it. Please. You will love every moment to take to yourself to do what you love, and being happy is so much more important than &lt;em&gt;problem-solving skills&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to charge up my camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- vallerie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[she/they]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS, I mentioned it, but seriously, check out Processing/P5.js - they&amp;rsquo;re very cool little projects, and, good to have a mess around with when you have free time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 10:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Vallerie. I try to make things which are pretty cool (not always techy things, just, things).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go by &lt;a href=&#34;https://pronoun.is/she&#34;&gt;she/her&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://pronoun.is/they&#34;&gt;they/them&lt;/a&gt; pronouns - using either is totally cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m based in the UK (as of right now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Github is &lt;code&gt;ValKnight&lt;/code&gt; - check it out if you want, I try to put most things on there (things non digital I&amp;rsquo;ll throw photos of on here).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌈&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first post</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 10:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all - this is the first post I&amp;rsquo;m making here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this space mainly because I&amp;rsquo;m annoyed at all the other options for putting my words make me hand my soul over to some shady company. While GitHub is no better (oh BOY they&amp;rsquo;re not better), at least here, I can take this site to another host relatively painlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to be doing more creative things in the future. I want to have a play around with Processing and see if I can make anything cool with that, which I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that&amp;rsquo;s me out! Have a great day all of you, and hope to be writing here soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Vallerie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[she/they]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
