<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Val Knight</title>
    <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Val Knight</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Content licensed under NPLv2</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 15:22:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.valknight.xyz/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Wanted to Do Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/i-wanted-to-do-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 15:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/i-wanted-to-do-photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been having thoughts for a while about how the compsci community has a really nasty feeling towards the arts. For example, the amount of jokes about arts degrees landing you a job in a coffee shop and that compsci is the One Good Field is frustrating to no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;14-year-old-vallerie&#34;&gt;14 Year Old Vallerie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go back, to 14-year-old Vallerie. I just got my first proper camera and fell in love with it. The photos were kinda bad, even for a 14-year-old, but even then, it was such a freeing thing, especially as I&amp;rsquo;ve never been big into painting or drawing. Going into college, I so badly wanted to do Photography. So badly. But, because I did well in Maths and Physics, I felt the pressure on me to do STEM things instead. Every time I heard of friends talking about their photography projects they were doing in class, I felt my soul get absolutely crushed, as, that was something I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bad-approach-to-teaching&#34;&gt;Bad Approach to Teaching&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kinda seeped into changing my feelings about the narrative of &amp;ldquo;We should teach kids to code!&amp;rdquo; that&amp;rsquo;s been pushed by the government here in the UK for about the past 10 years, while cutting school budgets (with the arts always being the first to feel this tightening of budgets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.valknight.xyz/images/personal/i-wanted-to-do-photography/guardian.png&#34; alt=&#34;Guardian article&#34; title=&#34;Source: https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/sep/04/coding-school-computing-children-programming&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re always told that kids need to learn to program because it helps with &amp;ldquo;problem-solving&amp;rdquo; and that we &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nEeD mOrE grADuATes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Personally, I think this is horrific. We should teach things because knowledge is valuable, not because big companies want new fresh code machines to sit at a desk and write another frontend for a database all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-to-do&#34;&gt;What to do&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, given the state of UK politics (very not good), I doubt this will change soon. As such, us compsci folks need to do more to promote cool projects that support the arts. One thing I adore is the project &lt;a href=&#34;https://processing.org&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt; which aims to promote &amp;ldquo;software literacy within the visual arts and visual literacy within technology&amp;rdquo;. This leads me into killing the awful stigma we have towards the arts, and specifically, those pursuing the arts at academic institutions like universities. (People who do/have done creative things as your degree or as your job, you&amp;rsquo;re HELLA COOL and I love all of you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping this up, this is a very long and disjointed way to write if you are in the same position of 14-year old Vallerie, and have a skill you so desperately want to pursue, do it. Please. You will love every moment to take to yourself to do what you love, and being happy is so much more important than &lt;em&gt;problem-solving skills&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to charge up my camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- vallerie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[she/they]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS, I mentioned it, but seriously, check out Processing/P5.js - they&amp;rsquo;re very cool little projects, and, good to have a mess around with when you have free time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to the Quiet Internet</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/an-ode-to-the-quiet-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 22:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/an-ode-to-the-quiet-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolutions&#34;&gt;resolutions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With new years, we all know of resolutions. I used to say I disagreed with the concept - often they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;strong&gt;pushed&lt;/strong&gt; onto us - things like losing weight, going to the gym. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do either. I&amp;rsquo;m kinda lowkey happy not doing either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year though, I did make a resolution. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it actively, and, I kind of started it before the new year as well, but, I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a resolution so I can join in. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get onto quieter bits of the internet. the internet &lt;strong&gt;I want&lt;/strong&gt; to use. So many people talk of burnout of social media, and for me, it&amp;rsquo;s not that - I love the people on places like twitter, and the close friends I don&amp;rsquo;t see nearly enough I can still talk to on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate the companies who PUSH things into my eyeballs. I hate the idea that every click, every interaction and every message &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be used to build some weird thing about me. I don&amp;rsquo;t want that. I want to talk to my friends. I love my friends with all my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;volume&#34;&gt;volume&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I describe this commercial internet as the &amp;ldquo;loud&amp;rdquo; internet. I use this, because, it&amp;rsquo;s similar to how I approach the &amp;ldquo;loud&amp;rdquo; world. I like being in the &amp;ldquo;loud&amp;rdquo; world (I.E parties, clubs, etc&amp;hellip;) not because I like the environment, but, I love hanging out with the people in my life I love. I much prefer quiet spaces - chilling with people on my sofa, or, being with a friend in a cafe, both of us reading our own books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;loud&amp;rdquo; internet I describe as places like Facebook, or Twitter. I love being there, because, loved ones! However, quiet spaces? They are so more my jam - spaces where, it&amp;rsquo;s okay if I take some time for myself, or, work on my own things while having a little off-beat conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My issue with the internet is, even in the past few years, the volume dial has been slowly turned up. Originally I had Tumblr - a space, where, I had my own blog, with people who only knew me by that username was idyllic. A friend then recommended me a site called &amp;ldquo;Reddit&amp;rdquo;. I loved it! It was the close community of Tumblr, just, without needing to break through the barrier of needing followers first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best bit was talking to people, similar to me, on small subreddits where there would be, maybe, 10 posts a day, if that. Those same spaces now have 100k+ subscribers, and Reddit itself feels a more scary place, with tracking, and it being ever more apparent people who don&amp;rsquo;t like people like me can and might well be watching my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;turning-it-back-down&#34;&gt;turning it back down&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the bit about accidental resolutions - late last year, I had the great idea of starting a blog (that&amp;rsquo;s this!). It would be MY space, to post project-y things, as well as just my general thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is all great, but, the quiet internet shouldn&amp;rsquo;t end at things like blogs. little, peer-to-peer messaging affairs would be so cool! It&amp;rsquo;s the difference between having to click to load an image (not, a blurred box where an image is) and bright interfaces with self-destroying messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this is a rambly post, but, over the last month or so I&amp;rsquo;ve had thoughts about it. I&amp;rsquo;m also trying to ensure anything on here is also longer, or, justifies being in this fancy place. for the more weird, off the wall stuff, I have an account on tilde.town now - my page is &lt;a href=&#34;https://tilde.town/~valerokai/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (if you are also there, shoot me a message! love talking to people who also use things like this)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stay safe y&amp;rsquo;all, and, hope you have a quiet and calm 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vallerie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[she/they]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-my-friends&#34;&gt;to my friends&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: am still going to be using the loud internet, in the same way I still go to parties! Just, if you want to get hold of me, maybe shoot me a text message or a telegram instead of a Facebook message, as I&amp;rsquo;m trying not to overwhelm myself as much as I did last year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 10:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Vallerie. I try to make things which are pretty cool (not always techy things, just, things).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go by &lt;a href=&#34;https://pronoun.is/she&#34;&gt;she/her&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://pronoun.is/they&#34;&gt;they/them&lt;/a&gt; pronouns - using either is totally cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m based in the UK (as of right now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Github is &lt;code&gt;ValKnight&lt;/code&gt; - check it out if you want, I try to put most things on there (things non digital I&amp;rsquo;ll throw photos of on here).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌈&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first post</title>
      <link>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 10:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.valknight.xyz/posts/2020-01/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all - this is the first post I&amp;rsquo;m making here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this space mainly because I&amp;rsquo;m annoyed at all the other options for putting my words make me hand my soul over to some shady company. While GitHub is no better (oh BOY they&amp;rsquo;re not better), at least here, I can take this site to another host relatively painlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to be doing more creative things in the future. I want to have a play around with Processing and see if I can make anything cool with that, which I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that&amp;rsquo;s me out! Have a great day all of you, and hope to be writing here soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Vallerie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[she/they]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
